{"tossups": [{"question": "<b>This state\u2019s first state bank issued the Holford Bonds which were prohibited from being paid out by this state\u2019s governor, William Fishback. The \u201cMinstrels\u201d and \u201cBrindle Tails\u201dfought over the results of this state\u2019s 1872 gubernatorial election. Powell Clayton served as governor of this state immediately after the Civil War, and his succession was the impetus for the (+) Brooks-Baxter War. Virgil Blossom fought for the integration of schools in this state against its governor (*)</b> Orval Faubus, who opposed the decision to send in the National Guard to this state\u2019s Central High. For the points, name this US state.", "answer": "<b> Arkansas</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "<b>This man discussed antebellum Southern poverty in his book</b><em><b> Journeys and Explorations </b><b>in the Cotton Kingdom</b></em><b>. A plan proposed by this man and an English partner led to the</b> <b>construction of the Ladies\u2019 Refreshment Salon and the Bethesda (+)</b> <b>Fountain. In 1887,</b> <b>this man designed a public attraction in Trenton centered on the Ellarslie Mansion. In an effort to protect the Muddy River, this man created Boston\u2019s Emerald Necklace. This man won an 1858 design competition with the (*)</b> Greensward Plan he created with Calvert Vaux. For the points, name this American landscape architect who co-designed Central Park.", "answer": "Frederick Law<b> Olmsted</b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Other Fine Arts - Architecture"}, {}, {}, {"question": "<b>This man financially backed a company led by John Gregory Smith. George Stephens and Donald Smith picked up shares this man held in a company for pennies on the dollar. Charles D. Barney helped this man run one company, and in 1849, this man was made a</b> <b>partner of the E.W. (+)</b> <b>Clark Company. The \u201cwire-house firm\u201d concept was created by</b> <b>this man who financed the Northern Pacific Railway and tried to make Duluth a metropolis. Helping the Treasury Department under (*) </b> Salmon Chase sell bonds during the Civil War, for the points, name this financier whose namesake company collapsed during the Panic of 1873.", "answer": "Jay<b> Cooke</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "<b>This man and his brother, Tizoc, are shown on a diorite slab sticking needles in their earlobes as an offering to the gods. This leader\u2019s attempts to build a canal to Coyoac\u00b4an were spoiled by a large flood that priests said was brought on by his murder of Coyoac\u00b4an\u2019s (+) leader. This man ruled as</b><em><b> tlatoani</b></em><b> at the height of his empire\u2019s power and was named after a dog-like creature with spines on its back. This man ordered 80,400 people to be sacrificed at the Templo Mayor after dedicating a new temple to (*)</b> Huitzilopochtli. For the points, name this Aztec emperor succeeded by Montezuma II.", "answer": "<b> Ahuitzotl</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>This man discussed the abuse of a young clerk in his 20-page autobiography</b><em><b> Waiting </b><b>for a Visa</b></em><b>. After meeting with Hammalawa Saddhatissa, this man accepted the Three</b> <b>Refuges and Five Precepts and prescribed the 22 (+)</b> <b>Vows to 500,000 of his supporters.</b> <b>With Mohandas Gandhi, this man signed the Poona Pact on behalf of depressed classes. This man wrote</b><em><b> Annihilation of Caste</b></em><b> and opposed special status for Jammu and Kashmir in Article (*)</b> 370 of the Indian Constitution. For the points, name this politician and social reformer who led a mass conversion of Dalits to Buddhism.", "answer": "B(himrao) R(amji)<b> Ambedkar</b> (accept Babasaheb<b> Ambedkar</b>)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "For the points, name this New Hampshire politician who was ordered by Andrew Jackson to implement the Specie Circular.", "answer": "Levi<b> Woodbury</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "<b>During this conflict, a trader named Rashid bin Masoud gained the favor of the German government by letting them borrow his private army. After this conflict, Kurt Johannes carried out a brutal scorched earth campaign ordered by the governor, Count Gustav Adolf von (+) G\u00a8otzen. During this conflict, hosts of the snake spirit, Hongo, distributed a mixture of castor oil and millet seeds that a man known as Bokero claimed would turn (*)</b> bullets into water. For the points, name this 1905 to 1906 rebellion against forced cotton farming by the indigenous people in German East Africa.", "answer": "<b> Maji Maji</b> Rebellion (accept obvious equivalents for \u201crebellion\u201d)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "This man\u2019s sister was the first female prime minister of their</b> <b>country, and her PTP party was the third incarnation of a party created by this man in 1998, the TRT or (*) </b> Thai Rak Thai party. For the points, name this former prime minister of Thailand, whose sister\u2019s name is Yingluck.", "answer": "<b> T</b>haksin<b> Shinawatra</b>", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {}, {}, {"question": "<b>After all of the Latin inhabitants of this city were forced by Grand Vizier Gedik Ahmed Pasha to relocate to Istanbul, they founded the</b><em><b> Kefeli Mahalle</b></em><b> residential quarter. This city, now called Feodosia, was transformed into a Black Sea hub by Italian merchants who</b> <b>purchased it from the (+)</b> <b>Golden Horde. This city was besieged by Djanibek Khan, who</b> <b>legendarily used catapults to hurl infected (*)</b> bodies over this city\u2019s walls in 1346. For the points, name this Crimean port, a former colony of Genoa that may have been the starting point of the Black Plague.", "answer": "<b> Caffa</b> (accept<b> Feodosia</b> or<b> Theodosia</b> before \u201cFeodosia\u201d is mentioned)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>This region included a fifty</b><em><b> verst</b></em><b> boundary along its western border where homes for certain people were prohibited. Sons of conscripts known as cantonists were exempt from living in this region. The 1882 May Laws further restricted rights in this region, which was</b> <b>the site of many towns known as (+)</b> <em><b>shtetls</b></em><b>. This region was formed by Catherine the</b> <b>Great out of territory from the Partitions of Poland. Subject to riots known as</b><em><b> pogroms</b></em><b> (*) </b>after the assassination of Tsar Alexander II, For the points, name this region of the Russian Empire where Jewish people were allowed to permanently make a home.", "answer": "<b> Pale of Settlement</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b>A ruler of this kingdom, King Jun, was overthrown by the foreign general Wi Man. A messenger sent to this kingdom by Emperor Wu assassinated a general escorting him to the border and then lied about defeating this kingdom in battle in order to secure a promotion. That blatant attack on this kingdom resulted in a retaliatory strike on (+) Liaodong which in turn sparked a war that resulted in this kingdom being dismantled and replaced by the Four Commanderies of Han. The fall of this kingdom, legendarily founded by Dangun, (*) </b>led to the rise of kingdoms like Baekje. For the points, name this ancient Korean kingdom.", "answer": "<b> Gojoseon</b> (accept<b> Gochoson</b>, accept<b> ancient Joseon</b>, accept<b> ancient Choson</b>, prompt on\u201cJoseon,\u201d prompt on \u201cChoson\u201d) (30) <b>This author described a Chinese woman who is driven to prostitution by Japanese</b> <b>occupation in his story \u201cThe Christ of Nanking.\u201d This author, who satirized the political culture of Taisho Japan in his novel</b><em><b> Kappa</b></em><b>, described the visual hallucinations that eventually drove him to (+) suicide in the story \u201cSpinning Gears.\u201d Conflicting accounts of a death in the woods are the focus of a short story by this man that was adapted into a landmark (*) </b> Akira Kurosawa film. For the points, name this Japanese author who wrote the suicide note \u201cA Note to a Certain Old Friend,\u201d as well as the short stories \u201cIn a Grove\u201d and \u201cRashomon.\u201d ANSWER: Ryunosuke<b> Akutagawa</b> (accept Chokodo<b> Shujin</b>)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "<b>This battle is the source of a phrase used in one country to describe very heavy fog. One side\u2019s vanguard at this battle was commanded by the Black Baron, Robert Munro,</b> <b>and a detachment of cavalry was commanded by Torsten Stalhandske. (+)</b> <b>The Rippach</b> <b>River played a significant role in this battle, and command fell to Bernhard of Saxe-Weimar after the death of one side\u2019s commander. Albrecht von Wallenstein\u2019s Imperial forces at this battle eventually (*)</b> withdrew to Leipzig. For the points, name this Pyrrhic victory for the Protestant Swedish Empire during the Thirty Years War at which Gustavus Adolphus was killed.", "answer": "Battle of<b> L\u00a8utzen</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>This man was assisted by figures like Sam Byrd, Jr. and Jack Bowler in his best-known action. Virginia governor Tim Kaine noted that this man\u2019s cause \u201chas prevailed in the</b> <b>light of history\u201d as part of a 2007 informal pardon. (+)</b> <b>Ben Woolfolk, one of his recruits,</b> <b>testified at the trial of this man, whose plans were foiled by flooding in the Brook Swamp. This blacksmith led an unsuccessful (*)</b> rebellion that was followed by his execution along with his brothers, Solomon and Martin, and twenty-three other enslaved persons by James Monroe. For the points, name this enslaved person who led a rebellion in Richmond in 1800.", "answer": "<b> Gabriel Prosser</b> (accept either underlined portion)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>This actress found stardom after appearing in Gustav Machat\u00b4y\u2019s film,</b><em><b> Ecstasy</b></em><b>, which was banned in the United States for its sexuality and in Germany due to this woman\u2019s Jewish heritage. After the Anschluss, this woman came to Hollywood where she found her</b> <b>greatest success in Cecil B. DeMille\u2019s 1949 (+)</b> <b>biblical drama,</b><em><b> Samson and Delilah</b></em><b>. This</b> <b>woman is also a member of the National Inventors Hall of Fame for her work with musician George Antheil on a radio guidance (*)</b> system developed in World War Two. For the points, name this actress and inventor.", "answer": "Hedwig \u201cHedy\u201d<b> Lamarr</b> (accept Hedy<b> Kiesler</b>)", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Other Fine Arts - Film"}, {"question": "<b>A member of this family served his wife a pie made from her pet doves and banned his sons from eating jam, because he believed it was not manly. Sylvia Brett wrote the book </b><em><b>Queen of the Head-Hunters</b></em><b> in 1970, seven years after the death of her husband, (+) Vyner, the last ruler in this family. The Japanese invasion of Borneo ended the rule of this dynasty, which began when the Sultan of Brunei rewarded the patriarch of this family with the Raj of (*)</b> Sarawak after crushing a tribal rebellion. For the points, name this unusual South Asian dynasty, also known as the Brooke family.", "answer": "<b> White Rajahs</b> (accept<b> Brooke</b> family, dynasty, or other equivalents before mentioned)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "<b>This man was told, \u201cYou have fought more with your pen than many have in our English navy fought with their enemies\u201d during the invasion of the Spanish Armada. Giordano</b> <b>Bruno spied for this man in the French embassy, and during the St. (+)</b> <b>Bartholomew\u2019s</b> <b>day massacre, this man\u2019s home served as a sanctuary to Protestants. Arthur Gregory, an expert at opening and closing seals undetected, was part of this man\u2019s staff, as was the cryptographer (*)</b> Thomas Phelippes. For the points, name this man who discovered Mary, Queen of Scots\u2019s plot to take over England, the \u201cspymaster\u201d for Queen Elizabeth I.", "answer": "Francis<b> Walsingham</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>This man was aided by Armenian Genocide survivor Hampar Kelikian after he suffered a gruesome injury in Italy. During a primary contest against George H.W. Bush, this man told Bush to \u201cstop lying about my record.\u201d During a (+) vice-presidential debate, this man claimed that the amount of people killed in \u201cDemocratic wars\u201d would be enough to \u201cfill the city of Detroit.\u201d Gerald Ford chose this man as his vice (*)</b> presidential candidate in 1980. Jack Kemp joined this man on a presidential campaign that was the first to create a website. For the points, name this man who ran unsuccessfully against Bill Clinton in 1996.", "answer": "Robert \u201cBob\u201d<b> Dole</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b>In 1890, the southern tip of this U.S. county was converted from an army fort as part of the Fort Mojave Indian Reservation. Antonio Armijo\u2019s route from Mexico to Alta California traversed this county along the Virgin River. This county was named for a senator and\u201cCopper King\u201d from (+) Montana whom Mark Twain called \u201cthe most disgusting creature that the republic has produced since Tweed.\u201d In 1931, the Pair-o-Dice Club was opened in this county, the first of (*)</b> many such locations that included the Desert Inn and Hotel Last Frontier. For the points, name this county, the most populous in Nevada.", "answer": "<b> Clark</b> County, Nevada", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}], "bonuses": []}